THAGANA MARK KIMARU

Python/Django, Back-end and Web Developer

Mayor RD No 17 Nairobi 4390- 0200 +254-726782953, +254- 732973772

thagana44@gmail.com

kimaruthagana@outlook.com

Link to Portfolio: https://kimaruthagna.github.io/
Link to Github Account: https://github.com/KimaruThagna

Currently pursuing a Bachelor's of Science degree in computer Science in the University of Nairobi while concurrently working as a programmer dealing majorly with web development in python within my own tech startup and also for an Automated facility company dealing with IoT as a software development consultant.

A recent winner of the google Africa Udacity scholarship in a mobile web specialist course and also a receiver of the Application Security Analyst Mastery Award from IBM. To top it off, I am part of a mentor-ship program called Kamilimu where tech students learn soft skills such as writing, networking and professional communication among others to foster values that increase their global competitiveness.

SKILLS

- a. Web scripting and design.
- b. Algorithm formulation and refinement
- c. Back-end development in PHP, MYSQL, python and POSTGRES.
- d. Program documentation and report writing.
- e. Python/Django for web
- f. Database Design.
- g. Business process refinement and formulation.
- h. Interaction with Linux systems
- i. Interaction with GIT.
- j. GRAPHQL/Graphene-Django
- k. API design using Django REST FRAMEWORK(DRF)
- I. Consuming Mpesa's Daraja API

EXPERIENCE

DOTSH-AFRICA, Kenya, Nairobi – Software Development

Consultant

FEBRUARY 2018 - DATE

Back-end development

Front-end development

Database Design

GIS View Development

API Interfacing

Venturi Systems Kenya, Nairobi - Co-Founder and Back-end

Developer

JANUARY 2016 - DATE

Back-end development

Database Design

Algorithm Development

stepwise refinement

API Interfacing

Free-lance Developer, Nairobi - Website development and

maintenance

OCTOBER-2015 to DATE

Web application development

Static web design

General consultancy on matters pertaining websites

EDUCATION

University of Nairobi, Nairobi - Bsc Computer Science

SEPTEMBER-2015 to DATE

Emobilis, Mobile Training Institute, Westlands - Web and

mobile development and Entrepreneurship

Jan-2015 to JUNE 2015

Graduated with a certificate in mobile and web software development and also, entrepreneurship.